PNC 需要做出选择:
PNC has a choice to make:
投资未来。
invest in the future.
这就是风能
And that's in wind energy
以及替代经济中的可再生能源。
and renewable energies in alternative economies.
我去过无数次
I've been to countless
示威、游行、抗议和集会
demonstrations and marches and protests and rallys in
在我早期的时候，大部分时间都是和我爸爸一起。
various places and in my early days mostly with my dad.
这对我意味着什么？
What is that meant for me?
我觉得这意味着这是一个我觉得很舒服的地方。
I think it means it's a place I feel really comfortable.
这是一个让我感觉像在家里一样美好的地方，
It's a place I feel pretty at home
这也是我对民主的信仰之一。
and it's part of my belief of what democracy is about.
这是我对贵格会信仰的一部分。
It's part of my belief of what Quakerism is about.
我爸爸非常正直。
My dad has tremendous integrity.
他言出必行，
He practices what he preaches
他愿意冒这个险。
and he's willing to put it on the line.
这些贵格会教徒是谁？
Who are these quakers?
是那个在桂格燕麦盒子上的家伙吗？
Is it that guy on the Quaker box?
贵格会教徒还戴着大帽子吗？
Do you still wear the big hats
还有大胡子吗？
and do you have the big, burly beards?
他们是阿米什人吗？
Are you like the Amish?
现在还坐马车吗？
Do you still ride in buggies?
现代贵格会与很久以前的有什么不同？
How are modern quakers different from long ago?
我的一些学生真的懂得平等和正直
Some of my students really know about equality and integrity
还有一些证词比如和平证词,
and some of the testimonies like peace testimony,
这对于今天的贵格会教徒来说是至关重要的。
that is fundamental to Quakers today.
过去是如何告知现在的，
How has the past informed the present
而现在又将如何告知未来？
and how will the present inform the future?
麦片盒上的贵格教徒其实是长老会教徒，
The Quaker on the cereal box is actually a Presbyterian
麦片公司决定使用贵格会的形象，
oatmeal company who decided to use a Quaker image
因为它让人关联到可靠性和质量。
because it's associated with reliability and quality.
在19世纪晚期,
This is in the late 19th century,
那时贵格会教徒已经非常融入社会,
by which time Quakers have become very integrated in society,
在商业上非常成功。
have become very successful at business.
到那时，贵格会教徒的形象就是在
And so by that point, the image of a Quaker would convey
传达质量、可靠性和完整性。
quality, reliability, integrity.
乔治·福克斯在1670年提出了一个
There's an advice from George fox stated 1670
不能赚取不正当的利润的建议,
about not making an undue profit,
但贵格会的价格很公道。
but they're being a fair price for something.
贵格会以固定的价格出售东西,
And so Quakers would sell things at a fixed price,
他们买东西的时候可不是小丑。
not haggar when they were buying things.
因为贵格会教徒的正直和诚实，
And this led to a great respect amongst the wider population
受到了广大民众极大的尊重。
for Quaker integrity and honesty.
人们开始信任贵格会教徒，并且说,
And people started to trust Quakers with their money and say,
“好吧，你能看管一下这个吗?”
"Well, will you look after this?",
因为他们知道他们会拿回来的。
because they knew they would get it back.
从那里，你得到了
And from that, you get
贵格会教徒参与了
Quakers being involved in the sort of
新兴的银行业。
nascent banking industry.
1915年,
In 1915,
实际上，教友派试图让国会通过一项法律
Friends actually tried to get a law through Congress
使用这个名字是违法的
which would have made it illegal to use the name
宗派作商业用途。
of a religious denomination for commercial purposes.
但不幸的是,
But unfortunately for Friends,
桂格燕麦公司有足够的游说力量否决这项法案。
Quaker Oats had enough lobbying power to kill the bill.
因此，贵格会继续是一个
And so Quaker continued to be a
相当有力的广告符号。
rather powerful advertising symbol.
我猜从19世纪末开始,
So I would guess since the late 19th century,
他们用数十亿美元赚了数十亿美元。
they've made billions on billions of dollars.
近400年来,
For nearly 400 years,
贵格会的领导者是他们基本的见证人:
Quakers have been led by their basic testimonies:
简单、和平、平等、完整、管理地球。
simplicity, peace, equality, integrity, stewardship of the earth.
向内看，他们受到神秘信仰的指引，
Inward looking, they are directed by the mystical belief
即每个人身上都有上帝的影子。
that there is that of God in every person.
他们也向外看，寻求改变世界。
They also look outward, seeking to change the world.
所有的贵格会教徒都不一样。
All quakers are not the same.
有无声的无结构化的贵格会议,
There are silent unprogrammed Quaker meetings,
也有福音贵格派教堂，里面有牧师和唱诗班。
but also Evangelical Quakered churches with pastors and choirs.
贵格会教徒分布在美洲、
Quakers are found in the Americas,
欧洲、中东、亚洲和太平洋。
Europe, the Middle East, Asia and the Pacific.
但是今天超过一半的
But today more than half of the Religious
教友派成员居住在非洲。
Society of Friends live in Africa.
这种显著的增长始于1902年，
This remarkable growth began in 1902
当时福音派贵格会传教士从俄亥俄州前往肯尼亚。
when Evangelical Quaker missionaries from Ohio travel to Kenya.
尽管有这些不同形式的崇拜,
Despite these different forms of worship,
正是他们对和平的共同见证，
it is their common testimony to peace
将全世界的贵格会教徒团结在一起。
that unites Quakers throughout the world.
我去看了一部关于移除山顶的电影
I went to see a movie about mountaintop removal
有一次采访一位女士
coal mining and there was an interview with a woman
说她把孩子放进浴缸,
talking about when she puts her child in a bathtub,
她知道水里有砒霜。
she knows that there's arsenic in that water.
我在想,
And I'm thinking,
“让我们做一个非暴力的直接行动运动”。
"Let's do a nonviolent direct action campaign".
这是贵格会教徒的基因。
This is something that's in Quaker DNA.
结束种族隔离。
That segregation be ended...
我们以前做过。
We've done it before.
我们可以再来一次。
We can do it again.
新泽西州的骄傲女儿，爱丽丝 · 保罗,
It took a proud daughter of New Jersey, Alice Paul,
多年来组织游行
years of organizing marches
绝食抗议
and hunger strikes and protests
起草数百份法案
and drafting hundreds of pieces of legislation
写信和演讲
and writing letters and giving speeches
和国会领导人合作
and working with congressional leaders
直到她和其他妇女参政论者
before she and other suffragists finally
帮助妇女赢得选举权。
helped win women the right to vote.
如果你把
If you were to put together
美国活动家的名人堂,
a kind of hall of fame of American activists,
无论是和平运动,
whether it be the peace movement,
无论是妇女选举权还是废奴主义,
whether it be women's suffrage or abolitionism,
当你看到这些名字的时候真的很震撼,
it really is striking when you look at those names,
他们中有多少人自己也是贵格会教徒
how many of them either were themselves Quakers
或者受贵格会教徒原则影响的人。
or who were influenced by Quaker principles.
我不知道贵格会教徒
I'm not sure if Quakers would have
会不会自称为革命者，
described themselves as revolutionaries
但他们肯定在努力
but they're certainly trying to
在人间建立神的国。
establish the kingdom of God on earth.
他们相信天堂将建立在人间。
They believe that heaven will be established on earth.
这是一场属灵的战争，他们称之为羔羊之战,
It's a spiritual warfare, what they call the Lamb's War,
提到了启示录。
a reference to the book of Revelation.
乔治 · 福克斯加入了这个组织
George Fox came into this group
被视为潜在的领导者和预言家。
and was seen as a potential leader and a prophetic voice.
据我们所知,
From what we can gather,
他很有魅力。
he was very charismatic.
他身材魁梧,
He was a tall,
是个非常强壮的男人,
very powerfully-built man,
我想人们已经准备好听他的了。
and I think people were prepared to listen to him.
他赢得了他们的支持。
And he won them over.
他很快就说服了很多人。
He convinced many people quite quickly.
1652年 乔治 · 福克斯来到彭德尔山，
In 1652, George fox comes here to pendle hill and
说他被上帝感动了
says he's moved by the lord
他有一个伟大的愿景，一个伟大的人民将被聚集。
and he has a vision of a great people to be gathered.
我们可以把那个愿景
We could really date that vision
视为贵格会的开端,
as the beginning of Quakerism,
作为教堂，作为运动。
as a church, as a movement.
他发现
And what he discovers is that
他可以和上帝有直接的关系。
he can have a direct relationship with God.
这是贵格会的基础
And this is really foundational for Quakerism
成为基本的信仰,
and becomes the fundamental belief,
他们不需要牧师或者书
that they don't need a minister or a book
来告诉他们上帝的旨意。
to tell them what is of God.
基本上，每个人都是牧师,
Everybody is to be a minister, essentially,
这是一个非常开放和普遍的信息
It's a very open and universal message
英格兰人民正在经历一些新的事情。
that something new is happening for the people of England.
贵格会教徒当然是历史性的和平教会运动的一部分
Quakers of course are part of the historic peace church movement
门诺派教徒和弟兄们,
with Mennonites and Brethren,
他们是民权运动的一部分,
they've been part of the civil rights movement,
他们有时是甘地和公民抗命的追随者。
they've been followers of Gandhi and civil disobedience at times.
他们在请愿和游说中扮演了关键角色
And they've been key in the role of petition and lobby
在三个半世纪里试图改变政府的想法
to try and change government minds over 3 and 1/2 centuries
贵格会的基本原则
The basic principles of Quakerism
最初没有包括和平主义或和平证词，
did not initially include pacifism or the peace testimony
但很快它就成为了核心信仰之一，
but soon it became one of the core beliefs
这对早期贵格会教徒来说是没有商量余地的。
that was not negotiable to the early Quakers.
人们普遍怀疑我是
I am generally suspected to be
一个破坏国家和平的普通人,
a common disturber of the nation's peace,
“国王的敌人，我,
"An enemy to the king and that I,
和其他人一起努力煽动起义
with others endeavor to raise insurrections
让整个国家陷入血海深渊”
to embroil the nation in blood",
”这一切都是假的,
"All of which is utterly false,
我在每个方面都否认,
and I do in every part deny it,
因为我的武器是精神武器,
for my weapons are spiritual,
它们带走了战争的机会，带来了和平”。
which take away the occasion of war and lead into peace".
1650年，他因布道而被带到法庭。
He was brought before the court for his preaching in 1650.
即便如此，他仍被视为一个危险的传教士。
Even then, he is seen as a dangerous preacher.
于是法官对他说,
And so the judge says to him,
“你不在上帝面前颤抖吗?”。
"Do you not quake before God?".
乔治 · 福克斯说,
And George Fox says,
“是的，你也应该这样”。
"Yes, you should as well".
它被看作是一个被称为贵格会教徒的贬义词,
And it was seen as a derogatory named to be called a Quaker,
实际上是20世纪早期
and it was really the early 20th century
在贵格会教徒开始思考之前,
before Quaker started to think,
“好吧，我们承认”。
"All right, well, we'll own it".
“我们是贵格会”。
You know, "We'll be Quakers".
所以这就是..,
And so this is where this...
我们现在都是快乐的贵格会教徒,
and we are all happily Quakers now,
但我敢说如果你回到18世纪,
but I dare say if you've gone back to the 18th century,
他们肯定不会乐意成为贵格会信徒。
they would most certainly not have been happy about being Quakers.
他们是教友派。
They were the Religious Society of Friends.
福克斯认为在上帝眼中，女人和男人是平等的。
Fox saw women as equal to men in the eyes of God.
女人和男人一样，可以当牧师,
Women, like men, could be ministers,
可以公开表达他们的信仰。
speaking publicly for their faith.
这是给我的大礼
That's been a huge gift to me
贵格会的女人有多么强大,
is how powerful women are in Quakerism,
女人的力量没有..。
and that the power of women has not...
至少以我的经验来看,
at least in my experience been held down,
但是很受欢迎。
but been really welcomed.
所以学习作为一个贵格会女权主义者意味着什么...
So learning what it means to be a Quaker feminist...
但我有一些很棒的老师。
but I had some great teachers.
玛格丽特 · 费尔是贵格会早期的关键领袖之一
Margaret Fell is one of the key early Quaker leaders
也是早期贵格会运动中
and a symbol of women's leadership
女性领导力的一种象征。
in the early Quaker movement.
她写书信和小册子，
She writes letters and tracts
神学上复杂且非常引人注目。
theologically sophisticated and very compelling.
她写了一篇名为《女性说话是有道理的》的文章,
She wrote one called "Women's speaking justified",
主张妇女有传教的权利。
arguing for the right of women to preach.
她在斯沃斯莫尔大厅的家中
She provided a safe haven
提供了一个安全的避风港，
at her home at Swarthmore hall,
为乔治·福克斯和其他人提供了经济支持和援助。
financial support and assistance to George fox and others.
我的感觉是，如果玛格丽特・费尔没有站出来
My feeling is that if Margaret Fell had not stepped forward
提供的各种物质支持,
with the kinds of material support that she provided,
乔治 · 福克斯不太可能会成功。
that it's unlikely that George Fox could have succeeded.
她自己也被关进了监狱。
She herself is put into jail.
她一度失去了一块土地。
She has a land stripped away from her at one point.
她说，
And she says,
“虽然我不再受国王的保护,
"Although I'm no longer under the king's protection,
我知道我在上帝的脚下。
I know I'm under God's".
一般来说，我觉得女传教士的日子确实不好过,
Generally, I think the women preachers did have a tougher time,
因为，当然，女人自己说教是不寻常的。
because, of course, women preaching themselves was unusual.
贵格会带来的颤抖和震动
The trembling and shaking that came with Quakerism
被认为是某种危险的歇斯底里症。
was seen to be some kind of dangerous hysteria.
一些贵格会教徒受到的惩罚之一
One of the punishments which some Quakers
会受到..。
would have been subjected to...
尤其是贵格会的女人会成为骂人的缰绳。
and in particular, Quaker women would be the scold's bridle.
本质上，它是一个笼子
And essentially, it is a cage
适合这个人的头。
that fits over the person's head.
里面有根金属棒，穿过舌头。
With a metal bar inside that goes over the tongue.
他们会被带到集市上
They would be taken to the marketplace
当另一个人引导他们的时候。
as the other person led them around.
他们正在拉动使笼子移动的链条。
They were pulling on the chain which made the cage move.
随着它的移动，金属棒在嘴里移动,
And as it moved, the metal bar moved inside the mouth,
也就是说牙齿断了,
which meant that teeth were broken,
下巴偶尔被打断，痛苦不堪。
jaws were occasionally broken, absolute agony.
成百上千的贵格会信徒,
The followers of Quakerism, hundreds of them,
将被关押在兰开斯特监狱的公共休息室。
would be held in the common room in Lancaster Prison.
他们会互相交谈。
They would speak to each other.
他们将在他们自己之间建立
They would create among themselves
一种非常强大的团结，以抵抗政府。
a very strong solidarity of resistance to the government.
我认为在贵格会主义中
Something that I think has been
已经犯下了几个世纪的事情，
perpetrated through the centuries in Quakerism,
这可以追溯到1600年代后期
and that goes back to the common room
兰开斯特监狱的公共休息室。
at Lancaster prison in the late 1600s.
在这30年里，大概有一万一千人被关进监狱，
Probably about 11,000 a put in prison during this time
有400多人死在里面。
and over 400 die in prison in those 3 decades.
他们因此而发展起来的
The strong solidarity they developed
强烈团结，使他们以
as a result of this carried them
更大的宗教决心进入美国。
onward into America with even more religious resolve.
他们在英国监狱中的肮脏、
Their experience in English prisons filthy,
拥挤而危险的经历
crowded and dangerous
引导他们参与重建监狱改革,
led them to join in the recreation of prison reform,
首先是在费城的胡桃街监狱
first in Philadelphia's, Walnut Street Jail
然后在城市的巨大东州教养所里。
and then in the city's massive Eastern State Penitentiary.
他们引入了单人囚犯监禁的概念，
They introduced the concept of single prisoner
每个牢房都有一盏灯，
confinement with a light in each cell
从天花板上开个小孔,
from a small opening in this ceiling,
表明囚犯可以从暴露于神圣中受益。
suggesting the prisoner could benefit from exposure to the Divine.
他们牢房里只有一本圣经,
The only book in their cell was a bible,
让他们祈求宽恕，和解过去，并重新开始。
to pray for forgiveness, reconcile their past and start anew.
这个解决方案可能对贵格会教徒有效,
This solution may have worked for Quakers,
但许多发现自己被隔离了数周、
but many others who found themselves isolated
数月和数年的人认为这是精神上的折磨。
for weeks, months and years saw it as mental torture.
这是一个有着意想不到后果的弥天大谎。
This was a whopper of an unintended consequence.
然而，现在仍然有成千上万的男人和女人
Yet there are still now tens of thousands of men and women
被关在美国监狱的禁闭室里。
shut away in solitary confinement in American prisons.
大多数美国人可能会
Most people in the United States would probably
把贵格会教徒的集中与特拉华山谷联系起来。
associate the concentration of Quakers with the Delaware Valley.
宾夕法尼亚州，费城。
Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
但是有大量的贵格会教徒
But there were large numbers of Quakers
早在17世纪60年代的 Carolinas。
in the Carolinas already in the 1660s.
他们是为了逃避新英格兰贵格会教徒的迫害。
They were escaping the persecutions of Qakers in New England.
清教徒不是贵格会的忠实粉丝。
Puritans weren't big fans of Quakers.
贵格会教徒不交教会的什一税。
Quakers didn't pay their church tithes.
他们不支持神职人员。
They didn't support the ordain clergy.
因为他们的证词，他们不会在民兵组织服役。
They wouldn't serve in the militia because of their testimonies.
所以他们在新英格兰不太受欢迎。
So they weren't much welcome in New England.
事实上，在1660年，有四个教友被绞死
And in fact, in 1660, four quakers were hanged
仅仅因为他是贵格会教徒。
on Boston Common simply for being Quaker.
不是贵格会教徒心怀怨恨,
Not the quakers bear grudges,
但我们还是可以给它们起名字:
but we can still name them:
玛丽・戴尔，威廉·罗便臣
Mary Dyer, William Robinson,
威廉·莱德拉和马尔马杜克·斯蒂芬森。
William Leddra and Marmaduke Stephenson.
一些早期的殖民地开放接受其他信仰,
Some early colonies were opened to accepting other faiths,
比如新英格兰的罗德岛,
like Rhode Island in New England,
在南部和北部罗来纳州也更加欢迎。
in the South, North Carolina was also more welcoming.
然后是宾夕法尼亚州,
And then there was Pennsylvania,
由威廉·佩恩于1681年创立。
founded by William Penn in 1681.
佩恩和其他早期的教友都不一样。
Penn is very unlike any of the other early Friends.
他家境富裕。
He's from a well-to-do background.
他的父亲是海军上将，在贵族圈子里活动。
His father is an admiral and moving in aristocratic circles.
他在牛津大学接受教育,
He is educated at Oxford,
但他在牛津的时候,
but whilst his at Oxford,
开始接受一些激进的宗教思想。
starts to pick up some radical religious ideas.
他父亲对此很不高兴,
And his father's not very happy about this,
让他离开了牛津。
takes him out of Oxford.
在英国公开宣扬和
It was against the law
捍卫贵格会是违法的。
to publicly preach and defend quakerism in England.
佩恩被关进监狱4次。
Penn was sent to prison 4 times.
他最著名的书《没有十字架，就没有王冠》，
His most famous book, "No cross, no crown",
其中他告诫国王,
in which he admonishes the king,
该书写于1668年，
was written in 1668
当时佩恩在伦敦塔服刑。
while serving a sentence in the Tower of London.
作为对他父亲佩恩海军上将的债务的偿还，
As a repayment of a debt to his father, Admiral Penn,
查理二世将现在我们所知的
Charles II grants the land that now we know
宾州的土地授予威廉·佩恩，
as Pennsylvania to William Penn,
于是佩恩就成了宾州的所有者。
and he becomes the proprietor of Pennsylvania.
为什么一个国王会在这个特定的时间
Why would a king grant this much territory
把这么多的领土赐给一个人呢？
to one person at this particular time?
其中一个理论是，
And one of the theories is that
如果这些麻烦的
they would have been very happy
贵格会教徒收拾行装离开英国，
if these troublesome Quakers would have packed up
他们会非常高兴的。
and left England.
根据一些说法，
By some accounts,
威廉·佩恩在1681年成为
William Penn becomes, in 1681,
世界上最大的私人土地所有者。
the largest private landowner in the world.
佩恩进行了我们称之为「神圣实验」的事情,
Penn sets up what we would call the Holy Experiment,
即渴望建立一个以敬虔原则为基础的国家，
a desire to have a state that's run on Godly principles,
在那里宗教宽容是有保证的。
where religious toleration is guaranteed.
佩恩的政府框架
Penn's frame of government
给予重要的宗教自由,
granted significant religious freedom,
虽然不能保证所有人的公民自由。
though not with a guarantee of civil liberties for all.
投票和任职
Voting and office-holding
仅限于白人男性基督徒。
were restricted to white male Christians.
佩恩将他对宽容的信念
Penn extended his belief in toleration
扩展到了与印第安人的关系上。
to relations with the Indians.
他会见了部落首领,
He met with tribal leaders,
尊重美洲原住民在土地上生活的权利,
respected the rights of Native Americans to live on the land,
并支付从他们那里购买的土地。
and paid for the land purchased from them.
遗憾的是，这个崇高的愿景并没有实现。
Sadly, that lofty vision was not to be fulfilled.
贵格会教徒发现自己无法
Quakers found themselves unable
控制其他来宾夕法尼亚州的人,
to control others who came to Pennsylvania,
他们渴望土地，最终完全退出了
hungry for land and finally withdrew all together
执行这些早期条约的努力。
from trying to enforce those early treaties.
宾夕法尼亚不是一个和平的王国，
Pennsylvania was not the peaceable kingdom
佩恩本人对这个地方的
and Penn himself was quite disappointed
发展方式感到非常失望。
in the way the place developed.
它的发展或多或少
It developed more or less like
像许多其他政治社区一样，在金钱和土地以及
lots of other political communities with factions and disputes
以及其他所有方面存在派系、争端和争论。
and arguments over money and land and all the rest.
威廉 · 佩恩是他那个时代的人，拥有大约9个奴隶。
William Penn was a man of his time and owned about 9 slaves.
我们只知道他至少给了一个叫雅菲 的人自由。
We only know that he gave at least one named Yaffe  his freedom.
佩恩死前30年,
30 years before Penn's death,
一些贵格会教徒已经开始公开反对奴隶制。
some Quakers had already begun speaking out against slavery.
- 想试试吗?     - 当然。
- Wanna try?	 -  Sure.
几乎从一开始，贵格会教徒就认为奴隶分享内在的光。
Almost at the outset quakers saw slaves as sharing the inner light.
值得注意的是，威廉 · 佩恩只在
Remarkably, William Penn spent only
他心爱的宾夕法尼亚州待了4年。
4 years in his beloved Pennsylvania.
1702年，美国和爱尔兰关于土地权利的
Legal conflicts over land rights in America and Ireland
法律冲突使他回到了英国。
brought him back to England in 1702.
1718年，佩恩死于债台高筑，享年73岁。
He died in extreme debt in 1718 at the age of 73.
但他对美国未来宽容、平等和
But his influence on America's future path of tolerance
自由道路的影响是不可估量的。
equality and freedom was immeasurable.
即使贵格会获得了权力，也有一种反应:
Even as quakers gained power, there was a reaction:
最安静的时期,
the Quietest period,
受到贵格会教徒的驱使，他们现在变得更加排外和严格。
driven by Quakers who now became more exclusive and restrictive.
大多数历史学家研究的是最安静时期的开端
Most historians look at the beginning of the Quietest period
是在17世纪晚期出现,
coming around at late 1600s,
一直持续到19世纪中叶,
early 1700s and lasting into the middle of the 1800s,
大约持续了150年。
about 150 year period.
他们不允许和非贵格会教徒结婚。
And marrying out or marrying a non-Quaker was not allowed.
这是不能获许的罪行,
It was a disown-able offense,
如果有人违反了此规则,
or it was something that if you did,
就会被开除会员资格。
then you could be dropped from your membership.
多莉·佩恩，更广为人知的名字是多莉·麦迪逊，
Dolley Payne,  who's more properly known as Dolly Madison,
出生于北卡罗来纳州新花园的一个贵格会家庭。
was born into a Quaker family in New Garden, North Carolina.
多莉的第一任丈夫是贵格会教徒,
Her first husband was a Quaker,
死于黄热病。
and then her husband died of the yellow fever.
多莉再婚后,
And when she remarried,
嫁给了一个非贵格会教徒，詹姆斯 · 麦迪逊,
she married a non-Quaker, James Madison,
之后多莉被开除了会员资格。
and she was dropped from membership.
但她确实在她的一生中
But she did maintain an affection
都保持着对友朋会的感情。
for the Society of Friends throughout her life.
如果你看看她的画像，
Although she didn't dress overly Quakerly,
她穿得不太像贵格会教徒。
if you take a look at her portraits.
她穿着很时髦，
She was quite fashionable
在白宫也是出了名的女主人。
and was known as quite a hostess in the White House.
就像最安静的人应该结婚一样,
Just as the Quietest supposed marrying out,
他们严格的信仰甚至禁止艺术、音乐和小说。
their strict beliefs even banned art, music and fiction.
厌恶艺术、厌恶音乐并不新鲜。
The aversion to art, to music is not new.
早期的贵格会教徒对此非常坚决。
Early Quakers were very very firm on this.
过了好几个世纪，
It took many centuries before
贵格会才开始对小说产生兴趣。
Friends started to warm up even to novels.
伟大的废奴主义者露迪雅 · 莫特
The great abolitionist Lucretia Mott
即使欣赏作者的作品，
would not read "Uncle Tom's cabin" even though
也不会读《汤姆叔叔的小屋》，
she admired the work of the author,
因为它是一部小说，不是真的故事。
because it was a novel and it was not true.
所以我们正在进化。
So we are evolving from that.
在这寂静中,
Here in this silence,
人们等待着神圣的指引来说话。
people wait for a leading from the Divine to speak.
他们没有牧师。
There is no pastor.
每个人都是牧师，并分担这一角色的职责。
Everyone is a minister and shares that responsibility.
到我天父的家园里。
Come into my Father's house.
到上帝的家园里
Come into God's house.
他欢迎各种各样的人:
And he welcomed people of all types:
不完美的人，罪人...
imperfect people, sinners...
他欢迎所有人来到上帝的殿堂。
He welcomed all into God's house.
我是个老师，
I am a teacher
我经常教我的学生，
and I often teach my students that part of respect
尊重包括学会相互信任、
is learning to trust one another
也包括你应该信任你的邻居。
and that you should be able to trust your neighbor.
建立信任需要很长时间，
Trust takes a long time to build
但摧毁信任似乎很容易。
and it seems like it's all too easy to destroy.
我们有一部分人
We have a certain segment of our population
发现恐惧是一种
that has discovered fear as a commodity
定期向公众推销的商品。
which is marketed regularly to the general public.
我是艾米 · 凯利，来自敬拜和事工委员会。
I'm Amy Kelly from the Committee On Worship and Ministry.
我想我们今天可能有一些访客在这里，
And I think we probably have some visitors here today
愿意告诉我们你是谁、
who'd like to tell us who you are
来自哪里，这样我们才能问候你。
and where you're from so we can greet you.
嗨，朋友们，我的名字是阿里穆塔尔。
Hi, friends, my name is Ali Mutar.
我要去 Old Chatham Friends 开会。
My meeting is an Old Chatham Friends meeting in New York.
我要去普林斯顿大学读博士了,
But I'm starting my PhD here at Princeton,
在那里呆5 ~ 7年。
so I'll be here for 5~7 years.
没关系。
It's fine.
我很期待...
I'm quite excited to...
我们可能会占有你一段时间。
We might claim you for a while.
是的，是的，没错，没错。
Yeah, yeah, exactly, exactly.
很多自以为是贵格会教徒的人。
Many people who think they've got Quakerism figured out...
然后参加一个典型的贵格会会议
and then visit a typical Quaker meeting
在南部或者中西部或者太平洋西北部
in the south or the Midwest or the Pacific Northwest
震惊地发现基本上是一种新教服务;
are shocked to find essentially a Protestant service;
里面有牧师、唱诗班、赞美诗、布道，几乎没有沉默,
a pastor, choire, hymns, sermon, virtually no silence,
前面有一个讲道坛，长凳面向前方,
a pulpit up front and pews facing forward,
还有一些彩色玻璃窗
and some cases stained glass windows
教堂建筑上的尖塔和奇迹
and steeples on the church buildings and wonder
“这是从哪儿来的?”。
"Where did this come from?".
这一切都可以追溯到复兴时期
It's all traced back to revivals that
在南北战争之后蔓延到了南方和中西部:
spread through the South and the Midwest after the Civil War:
卫理公会复兴，卫斯理神学。
Methodist Holiness revivals, Wesleyan theology.
许多贵格会教徒，特别是年轻的贵格会教徒,
And many Quakers, especially young Quakers,
想要打破最安静的时期。
wanting to break out of the Quietest period.
There’s version that you’re running out
♪ There's version that you're running out
♪ my way
作为其中的一部分，对沉默崇拜的强调较少。
There is less of an emphasis on silent worship as part of it.
我们偶尔也会这么做,
We have done it on occasion,
但是我们并不是每个部门都有
but we do not have it in every service
就像一些朋友教堂那样。
like some Friends churches do.
♪ 奇异恩典
♪ Amazing grace ♪
♪多么甜美的声音
♪ How sweet the sound ♪
福音派运动的一个途径就是
One of the ways that the Evangelical movement has probably
影响了我们作为福音派的朋友,
affected us as Evangelical Friends is,
在某些方面，影响音乐。
in some ways, impacting music.
最近几年,
In more recent years,
渴望接触新朋友,
with a desire to reach out to new people,
把人们带入信仰,
to bring people into the faith,
音乐是其中很重要的一部分。
music is a huge part of that.
所以现代风格的音乐更具吸引力,
And so more contemporary styles of music is more appealing,
特别是对一些年轻人
especially to some of the younger ones
这就是我们想要达到的目标。
and that's the ones that we want to reach.
♪ 你把我的世界握在手中
♪ You hold my world in Your hands
♪ 我相信
♪ I believe
♪你是我的一部分
♪ You're my portion
♪ 我相信
♪ I believe
♪ 你比我更重要
♪ You're more than enough for me
♪ 耶稣，你是我所需要的一切
♪ Jesus, You're all I need ♪
贵格会教徒多样性的根源也在于19世纪,
The roots of this Quaker diversity also lie in the 19th century,
当美国朋友以不同的方式回应时
when American friends responded in different ways
运动和更广泛的美国宗教文化。
to movements and the larger American religious culture.
第一次分裂发生在19世纪20年代,
The first of those splits took place in the 1820s,
当美国贵格会分裂时
when American Quaker is divided
变成了东正教和希克斯特教派。
into Orthodox and Hicksite groups.
这次分离的核心是
At the center of this separation was
来自长岛的贵格会牧师伊莱亚斯 · 希克斯,
a Quaker minister from Long Island named Elias Hicks,
成为贵格会争议的焦点
who became a lightning rod for Quaker controversy
他认为《圣经》的某些部分
when he argued that there were parts of the Bible
没有真正的灵感。
that were not truly inspired.
也许他们的历史都不是这样的
Probably no aspect of their history is
贵格会教徒更加自豪的来源
a source of greater pride for quakers
而不是他们在反奴隶制运动中的核心角色。
than their central role in the crusade against slavery.
露迪雅科芬出生在楠塔基特岛一个贵格会家庭。
Lucretia Coffin was born on Nantucket to a Quaker family.
她成为了美国最有名的女性，
She would become known as the most famous woman in America
因为她是废奴主义者和
for her role as an abolitionist and as a leader
为妇女争取权利斗争的领导者。
in the struggle for women's rights.
当她嫁给詹姆斯 · 莫特，搬到费城时,
By the time she married James mott and moved to Philadelphia,
她为行动主义做好了准备。
she was poised for activism.
1833年，莫特和其她女人联手,
In 1833, Mott joined forces with other women,
黑人女性与白人女性,
black as well as white,
无论是贵格会教徒还是非贵格会教徒,
Quaker and non Quaker,
她们组织了费城女性反奴隶制协会。
in organizing the Philadelphia Female Anti-Slavery Society.
它将成为全国最强大的此类组织。
It would become the strongest such organization in the nation.
露迪雅是费城宾夕法尼亚大厅
Lucretia was the driving force behind the construction
这项雄伟工程的背后推手。
of the imposing Pennsylvania Hall in Philadelphia.
它旨在成为该国
It was intended to be the center
废奴主义活动的中心。
of abolitionist activity in the country.
安吉丽娜和莎拉 · 格里姆基，教友会信徒,
Angelina and Sarah Grimke, Quaker converts,
是为数不多的南方女性废奴主义者之一。
were among the few southern women abolitionists.
他们是南卡罗来纳州一个著名的
They were the daughters of a prominent Charleston,
查尔斯顿奴隶主家庭的女儿。
South Carolina's slave-owning family.
两人都离开南方前往费城,
Both left the South for Philadelphia,
她们公开反对奴隶制。
where they could speak out against slavery.
1838年4月17日,
On April 17, 1838,
宾夕法尼亚大厅开放三天后,
3 days after the opening of Pennsylvania Hall,
安吉丽娜 · 格里姆基站在讲台上
Angelina Grimke took the rostrum
在两性完全融合的观众面前。
before a full integrated audience of both sexes.
作为一个南方人,
As a southerner,
我觉得我有责任今晚站在这里，
I feel it is my duty to stand up here tonight
为反对奴隶制作证。
and bear testimony against slavery.
我亲眼所见。
I have seen it.
我知道那里有无法形容的恐怖。
I know it has horrors that can never be described.
我是在它的庇护下长大的。
I was brought up under its wing.
多年来，我们的见证是
Our witness for many years
令人沮丧的影响
it's demoralizing influence
以及它对人类幸福的破坏性。
and its destructiveness to human happiness.
第二天,
The next day,
一群愤怒的暴民点燃了这座三层楼的大火。
an incensed mob set the 3-story structure of fire.
贵格会记者兼诗人约翰 · 格林利夫 · 惠蒂尔,
The Quaker journalist and poet John Greenleaf Whittier,
他是废奴主义者杂志《自由人》的编辑,
editor of the abolitionist journal "The Freedman",
从办公室抢救手稿后，
emerged from the burning building after
从燃烧的建筑物中出来。
rescuing manuscripts from his office.
露迪雅 · 莫特在贵格会
Lucretia Mott spoke out against
会议的各种场合公开反对奴隶制,
slavery in a variety of venues within Quaker meetings,
包括在公共场合。
but also in public.
她和其她女性愿意在混合的听众之前发言，
And she and others women were willing to speak before mixed,
这些听众有时被称为“混杂人”，
sometimes called "promiscuous" audiences,
也就是男人女人混杂其中。
meaning men and women.
这让费城那个时代的许多人感到震惊。
And this scandalized a number of people in that era in Philadelphia.
所以他们有时被批评为废奴主义者
And so they were criticized sometimes less as abolitionist
更多的是为了让女性成为公共演讲者。
and more for women being public speakers.
所以她参与了进来
And so she becomes involved and
这被视为第一次妇女权利会议
what was seen as the first women's rights meeting
1848年7月的塞内卡福尔斯会议。
the Seneca Falls Convention of July 1848.
五个人中的四个
And 4 of the 5 people
打电话组织那次会议的都是贵格会教徒。
who called and organized that meeting were Quakers.
电影，唱片,
Films, phonograph records,
以及描绘妇女参政者的漫画
and cartoons depicted the suffragists
无性别的女人试图模仿男人。
as unsexed women trying to ape men.
♪我在报纸上读到一个非常有趣的地方
♪ I've been reading in the paper of a very funny land
♪在这片土地上，女人就是裤子
♪ It's the land where the women were the trousers
♪那里女人是老板，可怜的老头是二手货
♪ where women is the boss and poor old man in secondhand
在19世纪和20世纪,
In the 19th and 20th centuries,
许多人试图继续让妇女保持沉默。
many attempts were made to continue silencing women.
72年来，妇女参政主义者不断地进行竞选和斗争
Suffragists campaigned and struggled successively for 72 years
在1920年赢得选举权之前。
before winning the right to vote in 1920.
苏珊·安东尼被判入狱
Susan B. Anthony was jailed
和男人一起公开投票。
for publicly casting a vote along with men.
爱丽丝 · 保罗被捕入狱。
Alice Paul was arrested and thrown in prison.
她被强行喂食时正在绝食抗议
She was on a hunger strike when she was force-fed
鼻孔里插着一根管子。
with a tube through her nostrils.
爱丽丝 · 保罗是这个国家第八代贵格会教徒,
Alice Paul was 8th generation Quaker in this country,
她很清楚他们不尊重权威。
and she was very familiar with their lack of respect for authority.
爱丽丝 · 保罗于1912年底抵达华盛顿,
Alice Paul arrives in Washington at the end of 1912,
她得到了国民美国人的授权
and she has a mandate from the National American
妇女选举协会举办游行。
Woman Suffrage Association to organize a parade.
就在伍德罗 · 威尔逊就职的前一天,
It will be the day before Woodrow Wilson is inaugurated,
它吸引了多达20万观众,
and it attracts as many as 200 000 onlookers,
这在华盛顿是闻所未闻的
which in Washington men was unheard of
以今天的标准来看甚至更大。
and even large by today's standards.
游行开始大约四个街区，人群突破了,
About 4 blocks into the parade, the crowds break through,
然后他们冲进了游行队伍中。
and they spill into the path of the parade.
大部分都是男人。
Most of them are men.
他们一直在喝酒。
They've been drinking.
他们伤害了所有对妇女的侮辱。
They hurt all insults at the women.
他们朝她们吐口水，撕扯她们的衣服。
They spit at them, they tear at their clothing.
那些妇女奉命不要反抗。
The women were under orders not to fight back.
这是非暴力抵抗。
This was nonviolent resistance.
警察对维持秩序毫无兴趣。
The police show very little interest in bringing order.
他们背对着游行队伍，他们在笑。
They turn their backs on the parade, they're laughing.
现在你可能会认为爱丽丝 · 保罗已经崩溃了,
Now you would think Alice Paul would had been devastated,
但是没有。
but no.
她看到，美国各地报纸
She saw that this near-riot
在头版头条上
on the front pages of newspapers
报道近乎骚乱的故事
across the America was a better story
比她的游行要好得多，
than her parade would have been,
事实上她是个公关天才。
and she was in fact a public relations genius.
她是真正的领导者和非暴力抵抗者。
She was truly a leader and nonviolent resistance.
第一批入主白宫的人,
The first people ever to pick at the White House,
华盛顿第一次社会抗议游行。
the first social protest parade in Washington...
她真的开辟了一条道路。
She really blazed a trail.
我觉得她应该参加选举
And I think she was to suffrage
公民权利的马丁·路德·金。
what Martin Luther king was to civil rights.
♪ 哎呀，哎呀
♪ Hurrah, hurrah.
♪为妇女参政权而欢呼。
♪ Hurrah for the suffragettes.
我一想到女人
I am so moved when I think about women
站在白宫前就
standing in front of the White House,
要求她们的投票权就很触动,
demanding their right to vote,
即使是在战争中。
even in the midst of a war.
这是一个非常现实的风险，女人进监狱。
And it was a very real risk and women went to jail.
但我就不能投票了
But I wouldn't have just been able to vote
如果不是这样的话,
if that weren't the case,
如果她不像在监狱里那样绝食抗议
if she didn't do the hunger strikes that she had done in jail and
就像她把其他女人拉进来一样
the way that she pulled other women in
对于实际可能性有着远大的愿景
and had a big vision for what was actually possible
她自己也冒了很大的风险。
and took tremendous risk herself.
我站在她的肩膀上。
And I stand on her shoulders.
PNC 声称是一家绿色银行，
PNC was claiming to be a green bank
他们也是一家有贵格会根基的银行。
and they also are a bank with Quaker roots.
很多贵格会机构仍然把钱投在 PNC，
And a lot of Quaker institutions still had their money in PNC
因为这种历史性的联系。
because of that historic connection.
所以在我们看来
And so it seemed to us to be a way
解决公正和气候变化的重大问题
to tackle these big issues of justice and climate change
通过追踪一个目标并持续战斗。
by going after one target and having a sustained campaign.
所以我们努力了五年,
And so we worked on, for 5 years,
让 PNC 撤资
getting PNC to withdraw that financing
从山顶移动采煤。
from mountaintop removal coal mining.
贵格会组织来到朋友信托基金
Quaker organizations come to Friends Fiduciary
作为一个团体，以纳入贵格会的价值观
as a group to incorporate Quaker values
对他们的资产进行财务管理。
in the financial stewardship of their assets.
因此，我们管理约350,000,000资产
So we manage about 350,000,000 in assets for
全国各地的教友会，教堂和学校。
Quaker meetings, churches and schools across the country.
因为地球贵格会行动小组
Because Earth Quaker Action Team
主要涉及贵格会教徒,
primarily involves Quakers,
有一种亲和力
there's a certain affinity
地球贵格会行动小组和
between Earth Quaker Action Team and
朋友受托人，因为我们服务贵格会组织。
Friends Fiduciary because we serve Quaker organizations.
朋友信托公司联合提交了一份股东提案
Friends Fiduciary co-filed a shareholder proposal
波士顿公共资产管理公司,
with Boston Common Asset Management,
我们的一个合伙人,
one of our partners,
要求陪伴
asking for the company
在这个特殊的情况下
in this particular case
报告他们的温室气体排放和
to report on their greenhouse gas emissions and
一般来说，在他们的融资组合中考虑气候风险。
looking at climate risk in their financing portfolios, generally.
我们做了公民抗命，2013年有了很大的增长,
We did civil disobedience and a big growth came in 2013,
我们一天做了15个动作。
when we staged 15 actions on one day.
今天的最后一个行动是逮捕7个人。
And the last action of the day was 7 people getting arrested.
我们在这里..。
We are here...
我们会战斗。
And we will fight.
我们需要每个社区都有一群天使般的麻烦制造者。
We need it every community a group of angelic troublemakers.
我们的力量在于我们有能力让事情变得不可行。
Our power is in our ability to make things unworkable.
然后我们继续在地理上成长,
We then continue to grow geographically,
2014年12月6日,
and on December 6th of 2014,
我们做了31个动作
we were able to do 31 actions
在哥伦比亚特区的13个州。
in 13 states in the District of Columbia.
所以我觉得一部分原因是
So I think part of what happened was
他们看到我们不会离开。
they saw we were not going away.
我们在成长。
We were growing.
我们变得更加大胆。
we were becoming more bold.
我们去拜访行政长官比尔 · 德姆切克的时候,
The time that we visited the CE, Bill Demcheck, at his house,
他出来和我们的人谈了一个小时,
he actually came out and talked to our people for an hour,
这是分配给我的，我们真的产生了影响。
and that was assigned to me that we were really making an impact.
所以花了5年时间，做了很多很多的工作,
So it took 5 years, it took lots and lots of work,
需要很多很多人。
it took lots and lots of people.
我们成功了，他们逃出来了。
And we did it, they got out.
他们非常有战略眼光，就像我说的，考虑周到。
They were very strategic and as I said, thoughtful.
我们利用贵格会崇拜作为我们工作的一部分，
We are using Quaker worship as part of what we do
这样很安全。
and that there's a lot of safety in that.
这里有很多关于社区的经验
There's a lot of experience of community which
我认识的每个人都渴望得到，尤其是年轻人。
everyone I know is hungry for and especially young people.
我认为年轻人尤其需要社区,
I think especially young people are wanting community,
不一定是为了这个
aren't necessarily looking for that
周日早上在教堂,
on Sunday mornings at a church,
而是希望能够在世界上有影响力
but want to be able to act powerfully in the world
并且有精神上的根源。
and have a spiritual rootedness to that.
约翰 · 伍尔曼是早期贵格会废奴主义者，
John Woolman was an early Quaker abolitionist who
他写了一本日记，这本日记
wrote a journal, which has been continuously in print
自1775年出版以来一直再版。
since it was published in 1775.
这本日记激励了很多人追随自己的良知。
And it's inspired many people to follow their consciences.
我觉得，伍尔曼能够
He has the ability to,
设身处地为他人着想,
I think, put himself in other people's shoes,
把自己放在印第安人的位置上
this active imagination to put himself in the shoes of Indians
他们不再生活在他们曾经生活过的土地上。
who are no longer living on the land that they used to live in.
他设身处地为奴隶着想,
He puts himself in the shoes of slaves,
设身处地为贵格会奴隶主着想。
slaves with Quaker masters.
他设身处地为贵格会的奴隶主考虑
He puts himself in the shoes of Quaker slave owners
并且意识到他们有要留住奴隶的压力，
and realizes that they have pressures toward holding on to slaves
解放他们的奴隶不是一个简单的决定。
and that just freeing your slaves is not a simple decision.
在约翰 · 伍尔曼所在的新泽西西部,
In John Woolman's part of New Jersey, West Jersey,
每20个人中就有一个是奴隶。
one in every 20 people was a slave.
让我们想象一下 John Woolman 来拜访
Let's imagine that John Woolman comes to visit
束缚他人的人。
someone who holds others in human bondage.
于是他来了,
And so he arrives,
种植园主说,
and the plantation owner says,
“欢迎，我给你拿点喝的”。
"Welcome, let me get you something to drink".
所以我拿出了茶和最好的银器,
So I bring out my tea and my finest silver,
然后我说，“你要喝点茶吗?”。
and I say, "Will you have some tea?".
他说，“其实我不喝银器里的东西”。
And he says, "Well, actually I don't drink from silver vessels".
“为什么不喝呢?”。
"Well, why would that be?".
“你知道银矿在哪里开采吗?”。
"Well, do you know where silver is mined?".
“在加勒比海开采，在巴西开采,
"It's mined in Caribbean, it's mined in Brazil,
它不是由自由的劳动力开采的。”。
and it's not mined by free labor".
我们谈论奴隶制，它是如何被反对的,
We talk about slavery, how it is opposed to,
所有的宗教原则,
all religious principles,
这是怎么回事。
how it is, ...
不仅对奴隶不利,
not just bad for the slaves,
但对奴隶主和他们的孩子不利。
but bad for the slave holders and for their children.
终于在约翰 · 伍尔曼准备离开的时候,
Finally as John Woolman is preparing to leave,
他把手伸进口袋,
he reaches into his pocket,
拿出一些硬币说,
pulls out some coins and says,
“哦，好吧，我知道你没有补偿
"Oh, well, I understand you don't compensate
你的仆人们的劳动”
your servants for their labor."
”我认为人们应该为他们的所作所为付出代价,
"Well, I think people should be paid for what they've done,
特别是对我来说。
especially for me.
所以我希望你把这些钱给你的奴隶。
So I hope you'll give this money to your slaves".
我们有两面，我们有灵性上的，稍微神秘的一面，
We have 2 sides, we have the spiritual, slightly mystical side
我们在世俗面都有自己的行动。
and we have our action in the world side.
John Woolman 就是这两方面的典型例子,
And John Woolman is a great example of these 2 sides,
相互平衡，相互通知
balancing each other and informing each other
我们如何体验神圣，我们内心的想法
that what we think inwardly in how we experience the divine
然后影响我们在世界上的行为。
then affects how we act in the world.
朋友们开始遭到那些人的反对
Friends began to experience opposition from those
看着贵格会教徒解放他们的奴隶,
who were watching Quakers free their slaves,
这是违法的。
which was against the law.
所以朋友们必须想办法绕过法律
And so Friends had to find ways of getting around the laws
并最终参与其中
and eventually were very involved
和地下铁路有关。
with the Underground Railroad.
有一个庞大的网络
There was a large network of
印第安纳州的反奴隶制活动家。
anti-slavery activists in Indiana.
Levi Coffin 很快就下了订单,
Levi Coffin became a quick order,
运动中一个非常重要的齿轮。
a very important cog in the movement.
有个赏金猎人来了
There was a bounty hunter who came
在纽波特寻找他的奴隶
looking for his slaves here in Newport
在屋外踱步
and was pacing outside the house
非常沮丧
and was very frustrated
因为他可以遵循
because he could follow the
追踪逃亡的奴隶到 Levi Coffin 家,
trail of fugitive slaves to Levi Coffin's house,
但后来线索突然断了。
but then the trail suddenly went cold.
他说，这里有一条地下铁路
And he said, "Well, there's an underground railroad here
而这个人，Levi Coffin，就是它的主席。”
and this man, Levi Coffin,  is the president of it."
作为回应 Levi Coffin 说,
In response, Levi Coffin said,
他会接受总统的职位。
he would accept the office of president.
他愿意接受任何职位，包括列车长,
And he would accept any office including conductor,
地下铁路的工程师或制动员。
engineer, or brakeman in the Underground Railroad.
重要的是服务
The important thing was to  serve
被压迫的人类的事业,
the cause of oppressed humanity,
照着他主耶稣所吩咐他们的去做。
the way that Jesus his Lord had told them to do.
很多朋友都是废奴主义者,
Many friends were leaders as abolitionists,
但当时他们并不被视为英雄。
but at that time they were not seen as heroes.
在那个时候，他们被视为人
At that time, they were seen as people
他们违反了常规
who were going against the norm
这是对宗教之友协会的挑战
and that was challenging the Religious Society of Friends
伸展，转变，改变。
to stretch and to transform and to change.
贵格会教徒是第一个
Quakers were the first to
整个宗教社会都有发言权
have the religious society as a whole say
奴役非洲人后裔是不合适的。
it was not appropriate to enslave people of African descent.
但他们在1776年这样做的时候就很清楚了
But they were clear when they did this in 1776
他们自己也想实行种族隔离。
that they wanted to have segregation themselves.
所以贵格会确实推迟了整合
So Quakers did delay integration
大部分贵格会学校。
of the majority of Quaker schools.
有几所贵格会学校
There were a few Quaker schools
在20世纪30年代接纳了一些非裔美国人。
that admitted some African Americans in the 1930s.
但大多数人直到20世纪50年代之后,
But the majority of them didn't until after the 1950s,
在1954年的决定之后。
after the 1954 decision.
最高法院的布朗诉托皮卡教育局案
The Supreme Court's decision in Brown v. Board of Education
意味着所有的公立学校都被要求废除种族隔离。
meant that all public schools were ordered to desegregate.
然而，非裔美国人申请者
Yet African American applicants
许多贵格会学校和学院
to many Quaker schools and colleges
仍然报告说他们被区别对待。
still reported that they were treated differently.
主要原因是,
The main reason,
实际上围绕着犹豫的成员资格和
actually around the hesitation for membership and
废除种族隔离的学校,
for having desegregated schools was,
有种族混合的恐惧。
there was fear of race-mixing.
You don’t have to ride Jim Crow
♪ You don't have to ride Jim Crow
No，you don’t have to ride Jim Crow
♪ No, you don't have to ride Jim Crow
♪六月三日，高等法院说
♪ On June the third, the high court said
当你骑在国家，吉姆克罗死了
♪ When you ride in the state,  Jim Crow is dead
You don’t have to ride Jim Crow
♪ You don't have to ride Jim Crow
我的行动主义不是因为我是同性恋
My activism did not spring for my being gay
或是因为我是黑人。
or for that manner for my being black.
相反，它是根深蒂固的
Rather it is rooted fundamentally
在我贵格会教徒的成长过程中
in my Quaker upbringing
以及灌输给我的价值观
and the values that were instilled in me
我的祖父母抚养我长大。
by my grandparents who raised me.
这些价值观是基于
Those values are based
单一人类家庭的概念
on the concept of a single human family
以及家庭成员平等的信念。
and the belief that all members of that family are equal.
贝亚德 · 拉斯廷出生在一个贵格会教徒家庭。
Bayard Rustin was born into a Quaker family.
他的祖母是贵格会教徒。
His grandmother was a Quaker.
他由祖父母抚养长大
He was raised by his grandparents
他一生都是贵格会教徒。
and he remained a Quaker all his life.
他祖母的影响是巨大的。
His grandmother's influence was enormous.
她不仅是一个贵格会教徒，而且也是
She was not just a Quaker, but she was also
围绕种族和种族关系问题的积极分子。
an activist around questions of race and race relations.
所以她是全国有色人种协进会的会员之一
So she was one of the charter members of the NAACP
并于1910年加入。
and joining in 1910.
所以她有这个双重传统，我认为他是继承人
So that she had this dual tradition that I think he was heir to
并标志着他一生的事业。
and marks his career through his entire life.
拉斯廷在民权运动中举足轻重
Rustin was enormously important in the civil rights movement
特别是在40年代，50年代到60年代的大部分时间。
and particularly in the 40s, 50s through most of the 60s.
他在介绍一些不同的
And he is instrumental in introducing a number of different
战术、策略、哲学融入到运动中。
tactics, strategies, philosophies into the movement.
一般来说，他才是被信任的人
Generally, he's the one that's given credit
把 King 引入非暴力直接行动。
for introducing King to nonviolent direct action.
I’m on my way
♪ I'm on my way
And I won’t turn back
♪ And I won't turn back
And I’m on my way
♪ And I'm on my way
I’m on my way
♪ I'm on my way
And I’m on my way
♪ And I'm on my way
I’m on my way
♪ I'm on my way
我现在带给你
I now bring to you
执行董事
the executive director
华盛顿游行委员会的成员,
of the committee for the March on Washington,
组织这一切的人 Bayard Rustin 先生。
the man who organized this whole thing, Mr. Bayard Rustin.
女士们先生们,
Ladies and gentlemen,
今天下午五点。
at 5 o'clock today...
你们所听到的领导人
the leaders whom you have heard
肯尼迪总统
will go to President Kennedy
传达这场革命的要求。
to carry the demands of this revolution.
现在是你行动的时候了。
It is now time for you to act.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you say?
拉斯廷的和平贵格会信仰也是如此
Rustin's pacifist Quaker beliefs also
导致他在第二次世界大战期间依良心拒服兵役。
led him to become a conscientious objector during World War II.
他为美国朋友服务委员会工作,
He worked for the American Friends Service Committee,
1917年贵格会成立的人道主义组织。
the humanitarian organization founded by Quakers in 1917.
我是贵格会教徒,
I am a Quaker,
300年来，每个人都认识贵格会教徒
and as everyone knows Quakers for 300 years
出于良心,
have on conscientious grounds,
反对参加战争。
being against participating in war.
我被判在联邦监狱服刑三年
I was sentenced to 3 years in federal prison
因为我不能虔诚地
because I could not religiously
认真地接受杀害我的同胞。
and conscientiously accept killing my fellow man.
美国朋友服务委员会成立了
The American Friend Service Committee was founded
作为提供年轻贵格会教徒的手段
as a means of providing young Quaker men
服兵役以外的另一种选择。
an alternative to military service.
Byard Rustin 是我们的员工
Byard Rustin was an employee
50年代美国朋友服务委员会的成员,
of the American Friend Service Committee in the 50s,
帮助撰写了著名的小册子《向权力说真话》
helped author the famous pamphlet "Speak Truth to Power"
关于朝鲜战争和核武器扩散
about the Korean War and nuclear proliferation
和美国社会的军国主义。
and militarism in American Society.
那本著名小册子的初版
First editions of that famous pamphlet
都无法解决这个问题。
in the 1950s couldn't grapple with that.
直到2013年，拉斯廷才终于得到了应得的报应
It was not until 2013 that Rustin was finally given his due
当他死后收到
when he posthumously received
奥巴马总统的自由勋章。
the Medal of Freedom from President Obama.
赫伯特 · 胡佛经常出现在这个时期
Herbert Hoover is seen by many of the period
正直，正直，高尚
as this upright, upstanding, virtuous
什么是教友派的象征。
emblem of what quakerism should be.
♪一旦我建造了一条铁路
♪ Once I build a railroad
Made it run
♪ made it run
让它与时间赛跑
♪ made it race against time
赫伯特 · 胡佛当选
Herbert Hoover was elected
1929年共和党总统候选人,
president on the Republican ticket in 1929,
大规模股市崩盘的那一年。
the year of the massive stock market crash.
面对日益增长的失业率和食品供应紧张,
In the face of mounting unemployment and food schiscity,
他坚持认为这在道德上是错误的
he insisted that it would be morally wrong
联邦政府提供帮助
for the Federal Government to provide the help
邻居之间应该互相帮助。
that neighbors should be giving one another.
因此，他拥有了大萧条
As a result, he owned the depression
还有全国各地的棚户区,
and every cluster of shacks around the country,
其中很多被称为胡佛山庄。
of which there were many became known as Hoovervills.
一直都是
all the time
♪说，难道你不记得，我是你的朋友
♪ Say, don't you remember,  I'm your pal
兄弟，你能给我一角钱吗？
♪ Brother, can you spare a dime?
理查德 · 尼克松是加州贵格会教徒,
Richard Nixon was a California Quaker,
这意味着加州贵格会
and what that means is that California Quakerism
更倾向于福音式的改变
tends to be more evangelically inflected
而不是其他类型的教友派。
than other kinds of Quakerism.
所以尼克松从小就不会有无声的崇拜。
So Nixon growing up wouldn't have had silent worship.
他就不会有牧师了
He wouldn't have had a minister
所以长大成人后,
and so becoming an adult,
尼克松坚信贵格会的传统
Nixon viewed himself firmly in a Quaker tradition
是他母亲留下的。
that came from his mother.
但这也是福音派的传统。
But it was also an evangelical tradition.
尼克松和胡佛是朋友。
Nixon and Hoover are friends.
我觉得这其中可能有某种联系
And I do think there's probably a connection
他们都是贵格会教徒
between them both being Quakers
就他们之间的亲密程度而言。
in terms of their close affinity to each other.
所以尼克松算是个门徒
So Nixon is sort of a protégé
共和党的这头老狮子。
of this old lion at the Republican Party.
赫伯特 · 胡佛,
Herbert Hoover,
当他成为第一位贵格会会长时,
when he had been the first Quaker president,
去华盛顿开会了。
had gone to Washington meeting.
尼克松不会这么做
Nixon doesn't do that
因为这是一个没有程序的会议
because it's an unprogram meeting
这意味着任何人都可以说话。
and that means that anybody can speak.
他们不能让他参加没有程序的会议
They can't have him in an unprogram meeting
因为他马上就要被袭击了
because he's just going to be attacked
在越南战争期间。
the entire time over the Vietnam War.
尼克松决定
Nixon decides that he's going to
举行一系列礼拜仪式
hold a series of worship services
在白宫东面的房间里,
inside the White House in the east room,
将邀请一些不同的
going to invite a number of different
宗教领袖来领导他们。
religious leaders in order to lead them.
只有受邀才能参加
It's by invitation only
还有很多收到邀请的人
and a lot of the people who receive an invitation
也碰巧是共和党的捐助者或人
also happen to be Republican donors or people
白宫特别想给人留下深刻印象
that the White House particularly wants to impress
让他们接近总统。
by getting them close to the president.
其他人认为他是个伪君子。
Others saw him as a hypocrite.
他们称他为“轰炸贵格会教徒”。
They referred to him as "The Bombing Quaker".
我觉得那是一个可怕的..。
And I thought that was a terrible...
词语的并列
juxtaposition of words
因为你怎么能把它和贵格会联系起来呢？
because how could you associate that with Quakerism?
我已经熟悉了贵格会的和平证词,
I had become familiar with the Quaker peace testimony,
这是... 费城的年度意义有它的副本
that it was... Philadelphia yearly meaning had copies of it
现成的。
that were readily available.
所以每一天，不管我们在哪里,
So every day, no matter where we were,
我早上第一件事就是去邮箱
I had to get to a mailbox first thing in the morning
这样我就能收到邮件了。
so I could get it in the mail.
我是说，所有这些关于贵格会遗产的讨论,
I mean, all this talk about Quaker heritage,
我想提醒他
and I wanted to remind him that
他的所作所为显然不太像贵格会教徒。
what he was doing was certainly not very Quakerly.
所以对于抗议者，尼克松显然很不高兴
So in terms of protesters, Nixon is obviously very upset
因为人们在抗议火腿,
by the fact that people are protesting ham,
抗议他在越南的行为。
protesting his actions in Vietnam.
他特别不高兴的是
He's particularly upset by the fact that
贵格会教徒正在这样做，因此他们的各种言论
Quakers are doing so and so their various remarks
尼克松对他的工作人员和其他人
Nixon makes to his staff and to others
这表明尼克松并不把他们当作真正的贵格会教徒。
that indicate Nixon doesn't see them as real Quakers.
例如，尼克松认为,
Nixon makes the argument, for instance,
贵格会教徒
that people who are Quakers
在白宫外抗议
protesting outside the White House
一定都是最近才加入贵格会的
must all have recently joined Quakerism
为了躲避征兵。
in order to, like, dodge the draft.
贵格会有一段非常光荣的历史
There is an very honored history within Quakerism
参与，甚至创造，产生,
of participating, even creating, generating,
设计非暴力直接行动运动
designing non-violent direct action campaigns
让广大人民群众参与进来
that enable masses of people to participate
尽管有反对意见，还是要做点什么。
and get something done despite the opposition.
“凤凰号游艇”载有自主定制的施舍船
The "Yacht Phoenix" has self-ordained mercy ship manned
由7名坚定的美国和平主义者组成。
by a crew of 7 determined American pacifists.
它的使命？
Its mission?
把医疗用品带到
To bring medical supplies to the
尽管红十字会警告北越海防港
North Vietnamese port of Hai Phong despite Red Cross warnings
而且没有国务院的许可。
and without State Department clearance.
我觉得我别无选择，只能献出自己,
I felt like I had no choice but to offer myself,
因为我被精神控制了。
because I was compelled by the spirit.
我认为一个关键的决定
I think a key decision
朋友们需要做的就是
that friends need to make is whether
注意观察我们的人
to pay attention to the people who look us over
包括年轻人,
and that would include young people,
因为这是一个精神探索的时代。
because this is a time of spiritual searching.
贵格会学校有什么特别之处,
So what is special about a Quaker school,
而不是一个非贵格会学校或公立学校？
as opposed to a non-Quaker school  or a public school?
我们在这里有什么不同吗？
What do we do differently here?
- 巷子-我们相信香料。
- Alley.  - We believe in spices.
香料，是的，香料。
The spices, yes. the spices.
香料是什么？
So what are the spices?
佛罗伦萨。
Florence.
S 代表简单。
The 'S' stands for simplicity.
S-I-M-P-L-I-C-I-T-Y.
- P 代表和平-和平。
- 'P' stands for peace.   - Peace.
“ I”有时候有点难，比阿特丽斯？
The 'I' is sometimes a little tough, Beatrice?
我认为它代表正直。
I think it stands for integrity.
正直是什么意思？
What does integrity mean?
这个问题很难回答
That's a really tough question
因为这是个又大又硬的词。
because it's a nice big, tough word.
阿兰娜，你..。
Alana, do you...
即使没人注意，你也在做正确的事。
You were doing the right thing even when nobody's looking.
真是个好答案。
That is a wonderful answer.
当你打开对话
When you open up the dialogue
让学生真正解决问题
and you allow students to really grapple with issues
用一种有意义和宽容的方式来谈论它,
and really talk about it in a way that is meaningful and tolerant,
他们就会觉得自己和这件事有利害关系。
then they feel like they have a stake in the matter.
贵格会的未来可能取决于新型的外联活动。
The future of Quakerism may rest on new kinds of outreach.
我们生活在互联网时代,
We live in the age of the internet,
所以贵格会教徒以一种全新的方式结合在一起
so Quakers are knit together in a really new way
因为我们是贵格会教徒
because we're Quakers have split
从17世纪开始。
over the years from the 17th century.
我们已经成为福音派的贵格会教徒
We've become evangelical Quakers
自由派教友会和保守派教友会。
and liberal Quakers and conservative Quakers.
在过去的几个世纪里,
And mostly in the past couple of centuries,
我们根本没有在这些分支之间进行交流。
we haven't interacted between those branches at all.
但现在我们上网了,
But now that we're on the internet,
也许会有什么激动人心的事情发生。
there might be something exciting that's about to happen.
也许会有贵格会的复兴
And there might be a revival of Quakerism
接下来的20年里。
coming up in the next 20 years.
♪他穿着朴素的衣服
♪ And he wore plain clothes
♪ And he was strong
♪有六万名贵格会教徒
♪ And there were 60,000 Quakers
When he was done
♪ When he was done
大多数贵格会教徒认为沉默是一种综合体验
Most Quakers view the combined experience of silence
与上帝之光交流
and communion with God's light
成为信仰的核心。
to be at the heart of the faith.
既有早期的朋友，也有现代的贵格会教徒
Both early Friends as well as modern day Quakers
总是被光引导着。
have always been guided by the light.
詹姆斯 · 提利尔，贵格会艺术家,
James Tyrell, the Quaker artist,
色彩受光的影响。
experiments and plays with color as its affected by light.
有些朋友将其视为神圣的光辉。
Some Friends experience it as divine radiance.
我参加了一个会议室，栗子山,
I attend this meeting house, Chestnut Hill,
我喜欢冥想的宁静空间
and I love the meditative peaceful space
只是躺下投降。
of just laying down and surrendering.
我喜欢暴露在天空中的元素,
I love the exposure to the elements in the sky,
还有风和云
and the wind and the clouds
还有那些你无法控制的事情
and the things that you can't control
或者比我们自己更伟大的东西
or that are greater than ourselves
它被屋顶的这个长方形框住了。
and that's framed by this rectangle in the roof.
我们所做的一切都是精神上的。
All of what we're doing is spiritual.
这是关于我们每个人心中的上帝。
It is about that of God in each of us.
而是我们对彼此的尊重。
It's about the respect we have for each other.
而是我们每个人肩负的责任。
It's about the responsibility we each carry.
所以我很高兴能见到这些人,
And so it's been so exciting to me to see people,
无论他们最终是否成为贵格会教徒,
whether they become ultimately Quaker or not,
发现安静地坐在一群人中意味着什么？
finding what does it mean to sit in a gathered group in silence?
从沉默中说出来意味着什么,
What does it mean to speak coming out of that silence,
说出那么深刻的事实吗？
to speak that deep, capital T, truth?
所以我看到这些，像，人开花
And so I've seen these, like, people blossoming
因为这是一种表达“是的，我不需要
because it's a way of saying, "Yes, I don't have to have
我的信仰在这里，我的行动主义在这里”。
my faith over here and my activism over here".